airbusgroup.com 2017-12-01

# Privacy policy

**1\. Privacy Statement**

Airbus appreciates your interest in its products and services and your visit to our web site. Your privacy is important to us and we want you to feel comfortable visiting our site. The protection of your privacy in the processing of your personal data is an important concern to which we pay special attention during our business processes. Personal data collected during visits to our web site are processed by us according to the legal provisions valid for the countries in which the web sites are maintained. In addition, our Corporate Policy for Personal Data Protection covers also the processing of Customer and Partner Data which is applicable company-wide for Airbus. The Airbus web site may include, however, links to other web sites which are not covered by this privacy statement.

Airbus respects your privacy and your personal data.

**2\. Collection and processing of personal data**

When you visit our web site, our web server automatically records your IP address, the web site from which you visit us, the web pages you actually visit and the date and length of your visit. Personal data is only stored if volunteered by you, for example in the context of a registration, a survey, a competition or in execution of a contract.

You do not have to give us any personal information in order to perform job searches. Nevertheless, to apply or register in the eRecruiting@Airbus tool, you will have to type your personal username/email address and a password.

In some areas of the eRecruiting@Airbus tool, it is required that you provide personal data, including your name, address, e-mail address and telephone number.

From these your identity as an Airbus employee, if so, is discernible for the aim of identity proofing.

If you use the eRecruiting@Airbus tool to build a CV to put in the jobseekers’ CVs database, then you will be providing the HR Department with personal data which will be used in accordance with this Statement. We strongly suggest that your CV should not contain data relating to your (i) racial or ethnic origin (ii) political beliefs (iii) philosophical or religious beliefs (iv) membership of a trade union or political party (v) physical or mental health (vi) sexual life or (vii) the commission of criminal offences or proceedings. If your CV does contain such data, then you agree that we may retain this information and use it in accordance with this Statement.

**3\. Use and Disclosure of Personal Data and Purpose Specification**

Airbus will use your personal data for the sole purpose of technical administration of the web site, customer administration, product surveys and marketing, only to the extent necessary in each specific case. We will only disclose your data to governmental authorities in cases where it is required by law. Our employees, agencies, and retailers are obliged by us to respect confidentiality.

Airbus uses the information gathered on the web application eRecruiting@Airbus, whether personal, demographic, collective or technical, for the purposes of administering and managing your registration, responding to any queries you may have, operating and improving the website, fostering a positive user experience and delivering the products and services that we offer to jobseekers and hiring managers.

If you have so agreed when registering, or subsequently, or if permitted by applicable law, we may use your contact information in order to send you e-mail or other communications regarding updates on the website, such as new opportunities and additional listings which may be of interest to you.

**4\. Disclosure of information to others than the HR Department**

We disclose to HR operators or line managers your personal information, combined personal and demographic information, as set forth below.

We may disclose such information to the involved parties if you consent to such disclosure, either because you are considered for a vacancy you have applied for, or because you made your CV available to be contacted for job opportunities. You may make your CV unavailable again at any time.

We may disclose such information if legally required to do so, if requested to do so by a governmental entity or regulatory authority or if we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal processes; (b) prevent a crime or protect national security; or (c) protect the personal safety of users or the public.

**5\. CVs**

Since eRecruiting@Airbus is a career site within Airbus' perimeter, we provide you with the option of putting your CV in the database. There are two ways of doing this:

You can store your CV in the eRecruiting@Airbus database, but not allow it to be searchable by potential employers. Not allowing your CV to be available means that you can use it to apply for jobs online, but recruiters will not have access to search for it through the CV database.

If you allow your CV to be available, then all HR parties with access to the search function in the CV database will have access to your CV. You can also allow your CV to be available but remove your contact details. However, you should be aware that in this situation if you have a rare skill, it may still be possible for a recruiter to identify you even without your contact details being included. If you are worried about being identified, you should not include specific skills or details by which you could be identified.

Airbus is committed to limiting the access to the searchable CV database only to Airbus Human Resources professionals involved in recruitment activities. You may remove your CV from the eRecruiting@Airbus searchable database at any time. However, recruiters and operators who have access to the database may have retained a copy of your CV in their own files: in this case these recruiters and operators are directly responsible for treating the copy of your CV in compliance with the Airbus Data Protection Policy.

If you provide us with details of a referee, it is your responsibility to ensure that the person is aware that you have forwarded his/her details and has consented in writing for you to do so.

**6\. Updating or deleting your information**

You may review, correct, update or change your CV at any time. Simply log into your eRecruiting@Airbus account, go to your CV, review it and, if you wish, edit it with the options provided.

If you wish to delete your information in the eRecruiting@Airbus tool at any time, please contact us at erecruiting@airbus.com. An e-mail will be sent to you to confirm that your information has been deleted.

If you wish to revoke your consent to this Privacy Statement, please contact us at erecruiting@airbus.com. However, please note that if you do withdraw your consent, you may not be able to use the relevant services and your account profile information will be deleted.

Since Airbus believes that managing your career is a life-long process, we retain all the information we gather about you in an effort to make your repeat use with us more efficient, practical and relevant until you change or remove your personal data as detailed above.

**7\. Freedom of Choice**

We should like to use your data to inform you about our products and services and where applicable request your opinion. Naturally your participation is completely voluntary. Should you not consent, you can inform us at any time so that we can suppress your data accordingly. Please refer to the respective web site for further information.

**8\. Non-Personal Data Collected Automatically**

When you access our Web sites, we may automatically (i.e., not by registration) collect non-personal data (e.g. type of Internet browser and operating system used, domain name of the Web site from which you came, number of visits, average time spent on the site, pages viewed). We may use this data and share it with our worldwide affiliates to monitor the attractiveness of our Websites and improve their performance or content.

**9\. Cookies**

Airbus uses cookies to record the preferences of visitors, to enable us to optimize the design of our web site. Cookies are small files which are stored on your hard drive. They ease navigation, and increase the user-friendliness of a web site. Cookies also help us to identify the most popular sections of our web site. This enables us to provide content that is more accurately suited to your needs, and in so doing improve our service. Cookies can be used to determine whether there has been any contact between us and your computer in the past. Only the cookie on your computer is identified. Personal details can be saved in cookies, provided that you have consented to this, for example, in order to facilitate secure online access so that you not need to enter your user ID and password again.

If you choose not to accept cookies, you can still visit our website. Most browsers automatically accept cookies. You can prevent cookies from being stored on your hard drive by setting your browser to not accept cookies. The exact instructions for this can be found in the manual for your browser. You can delete cookies already on your hard drive at any time. However, if you choose not to accept cookies it may result in a reduced availability of the services provided by our web site.

For the purpose of statistical analysis Airbus uses Adobe Analytics. If you do not wish Airbus to collect and analyze statistical data of your visit you may object at for the future use of your date at any time.

**10\. Withdrawal of consent for the use of 3rd party cookies**

Visitors to our website can withdraw their consent for their pseudonymized visitor data to be stored, so that it is no longer collected (recorded) in future. For exclusion from our website controlling, a cookie with the name "allow-cookie” is set by the domain airbus.com. This exclusion applies as long as the cookie is not deleted. The cookie is set for the named domain for each browser and computer. Thus, for example, if you visit our website at home and at work, or if you use different browsers, you need to set the cookie on each computer and browser.

To complete withdrawal of consent, please click the Send button

**11\. Withdrawal of consent for the use of 1st party cookies**

Visitors to our website can withdraw their consent for their pseudonymized visitor data to be stored, so that it is no longer collected (recorded) in future.

For exclusion from Adobe Analytics Web controlling, a cookie with the name "allow-cookie” is set by the domain eads.com. This exclusion applies as long as the cookie is not deleted. The cookie is set for the named domain for each browser and computer. Thus, for example, if you visit our website at home and at work, or if you use different browsers, you need to set the cookie on each computer and browser.

To complete withdrawal of consent, please click on the Send button.

**12\. Consent for extended use of cookies**

Our statistical service provider uses what are known as persistent cookies when you visit our website. This helps us to recognise you when you visit our website again. The recognition affected by these cookies optimises the content of our website. In the standard setting, only cookies with a maximum lifetime of 6 months are permitted. However, to optimise our website for the long term and to provide specific content or user information, we also require cookie information over a longer period. By consenting to extended cookie use, you are giving us your agreement to extend the lifetime of the cookies set to a maximum of 12 months. To give your consent, please click on the Send button.

You can withdraw your consent at any time, either by deleting your cookies or by setting an opt-out cookie.

**13\. Security**

Airbus uses all technical and organizational security measures in order to protect the data we have under our control against accidental or intentional manipulation, loss, destruction and against access by unauthorized persons. Our security procedures are continually enhanced as new technology becomes available.

**14\. Children**

Airbus does not knowingly collect personal data from children without insisting that they seek prior parental consent if required by applicable law. We will only use or disclose personal data about a child to the extent permitted by law, to seek parental consent pursuant to local law and regulations or to protect a child. The definition of "child" or "children" should take into account applicable laws as well as national and regional cultural customs.

**15\. Freedom of Information**

Upon written request, Airbus or its representatives will inform you by letter without delay what personal data is stored by us as defined by applicable law.   Should such data be incorrect, we will at your request correct that information for you, also as a registered user you have the option of viewing, deleting or amending your personal data yourself.

Should you have questions regarding the processing of your personal data you can refer to the Airbus Data Protection Officer, who is also available for enquiries, suggestions or complaints.

Airbus Data Protection Compliance Officer  
Airbus SAS  
HAP  
1 rond-point Maurice Bellonte  
31700 Toulouse  
France

This Privacy Statement was last updated in June 2017
